Motivation
What's wrong, Yukko?
I don't have the motivation to do anything.
What are you talking about?
We're high school students.
It's the start of the new semester.
If you just start doing things,
motivation will come to you naturally.
But I don't have the motivation to start.
How do I find the motivation for that?
The motivation to start?
You just have to do it!
All right!
I wish I could be a simpleton.
Shinonome Laboratory
Professor, please wake up!
Nichijou:
My Ordinary
Life, Part 1
Good morning.
What are you doing?
Today's breakfast is fried fish.
What? Omelet rice...
You had that yesterday.
Fish is very nutritious.
Don't be picky.
Otherwise, you won't grow...
Ah, that's our breakfast!
What?
Oh, no!
This isn't a robot part, but a... Uh...
It ran away.
Wait!
See you later.
Maybe that cat's down on his luck.
I'm going to crash!
kokeshi
akabeko
salmon
Mio-chan, selamat pagi.
Yukko, good morning.
What should I do?
I forgot my student ID.
What? No response to selamat pagi?
You don't think an upperclassman
will call me out on it, do you?
If that happens,
why not just say you're a third year?
That won't solve anything.
What? Was that thunder?
But it's sunny.
We might have a sudden storm!
Showers and hail!
It's raining kokeshi...
A-Are you okay, Yukko?
I can't believe it's a kokeshi...
That was a surprise.
I wonder where it came from.
I don't know...
But not many people ever
get struck by a kokeshi!
That hardly ever happens
to anyone, right?
It doesn't happen to anyone.
Maybe I'm lucky!
I'm not lucky...
Yukko, are you okay?
I can't believe it's an akabeko...
An akabeko...
No, I'm not unlucky.
Think of it this way, Mio-chan.
I should be glad nothing
perishable struck me.
It could have been worse.
It's salmon!
Prefectural High School
Morning.
Good morning.
Mai-chan, good morning.
Selamat pagi!
Good morning.
Mai-chan, what are you reading?
A real estate magazine.
What? Mai-chan, are you moving?
I haven't decided.
No response to selamat pagi?
Fine. I'll have to put this phrase to sleep.
Yukko...
Selamat malam.
Mai-chan! Don't you mean selamat pagi?
What language is that?
H-Homeroom is starting...
When I arrived at school this morning,
I found this in my shoe locker.
Did someone put this in there?
U-Um, if anyone knows
who did this, please tell me!
Mio-chan, who would do such a thing?
Could it be a prank?
Maybe it's a student with feelings for her.
But a statue of the Maitreya Buddha?
I guess I can understand what it's like
to have hopeless feelings
for someone, though.
You mean like your feelings
for Sasahara-senpai?
Y-You idiot!
Where am I?
I need to get home.
The professor must be worried,
and I left the stove on.
I can't get down!
I can't find my chopsticks.
Or my slipper.
What am I going to do?
I lost my arm!
They'll all know I'm a robot...
Here we go.
Wonderful
I'm finished.
If you don't hurry up and eat,
we'll be late to fifth period.
Huh? I thought you liked wieners.
I save the tastiest part
of my lunch for last.
I wrap up by saying that it's delicious.
Here's the first one!
Nichijou:
My Ordinary
Life, Part 2
It slipped through!
It's over!
Not yet!
One...
Two...
Three!
Safe!
You're out!
Jeez, Mio-chan.
It's the three-second rule.
No, you're already way out!
Delicious!
She's such an idiot...
First comes rock! Then comes paper...
You can't throw all of them.
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot!
Okay!
Good morning, everyone.
Spring is here,
and a new year has begun,
but it's still cold.
I'm twice as cold as any of you, though.
Nichijou: My Ordinary Life, Part 3
In any case, be sure not to catch a cold.
Promise me you won't, all right?
If you don't listen to me...
I'll become the principal of another school.
Mio-chan, Mio-chan.
What? We'll get in trouble for talking.
Do you think the principal knows
how old his jokes are?
He must know, better than anyone else,
no one thinks they're funny...
I don't know.
Maybe he knows they're not funny,
but he wants to show today's
corrupt youth what hard work means.
If that's the case,
this principal is quite the schemer!
Mai-chan?
Mai-chan...
You don't think she really found his joke...
I've never seen Mai-chan
laugh so hard before...
All right, let's see!
Mai-chan...
Why do I feel
if I say anything right now,
I'll lose everything?
Yukko...
Oh, sorry. Never mind.
I'll wait until she notices.
Squid Leg
Next, we have a message for the
student body, from Sakurai-sensei.
Sakurai-sensei, please go ahead.
Um, Sakurai-sensei.
Yes!
I'm student adviser Sakurai.
Please excuse me...
I get nervous in front of so many people.
I can't act like this.
I'll never become the teacher I want to be.
I have to do what I must!
I know!
Recently, I've seen a lot of
goats around school.
Please do not bring your goats to school!
Goats?
What's wrong with goats?!
Arriving by goat doesn't
violate school policy!
What? Uh...
Mio-chan, isn't that Sasahara-senpai?
What? Really...
I will allow goats!
You can't. Can! Not!
I forbid it!
There's no way you can bring a goat!
Don't say that, Tachibana Misato.
Why must I walk on my own two legs?
As the Sasahara family's eldest son...
Who cares if you're the
Sasahara family's oldest son?
You're still ordinary farmers!
So what?
What's wrong with an eldest son
calling himself the eldest son?
Sasahara-kun's family are farmers.
I feel deceived.
That goat by the bicycles
was Sasahara-senpai's...
Sasahara-senpai came for
me on a white goat!
Happy new year.
Me, too...
Mio-chan!
Talking on your phone while on your bike
is extremely dangerous.
Don't do it! Finally...
I found a Maitreya in my
shoe locker this morning.
I don't find this sort of thing acceptable!
Excuse me! Coming through...
Maitreya...
Mai-chan, don't stop!
Is this déjà vu?
Who did it?
I won't be mad, so raise your hand.
We'll stay here all day,
until you turn yourself in!
Who did it?
Turn yourself in.
I heard it was your birthday,
Sakurai-sensei...
Oh, really? You don't like Maitreya?
I thought you'd like it for your birthday,
but you didn't want a Maitreya statue.
— Principal
This concludes the morning announcements.
Thank you for your work
up to this point, Principal.
Vice-Principal?
Button
Don't you feel compelled
to push the fire alarm button?
You're right, I do.
Why don't you push it?
When I pushed it before,
it didn't make any noise.
Really?
A fire?
No way!
What do we do? Should we run?
Let's head outside!
Stop pushing me!
You pushed me first!
What are you talking about?
I've always hated you!
Cut it out! Someone could die!
Just run! You can argue later!
Excuse me.
Excuse me, but do you know
what K.Y. means?
Excuse me.
What does K.Y. mean?
Excuse me, but could you
tell me about K.Y.?
Help me!
Hey!
Captain, what's K.Y.?
Someone clueless, like you.
Class 2-P, Sasahara Koujirou.
Requirements
and Affairs
Please see Tomioka in the
faculty office immediately.
I know it doesn't violate school policy,
but why does it have to be a goat?
Can't we work this out?
If you dislike walking, you could ride a bike.
Anything but a goat.
Sir.
It's Tomioka.
Tomioka.
Call me sensei.
Sensei, could you call him
Sasahara Kojiro, rather than goat?
He's a goat for now.
Nichijou:
My Ordinary
Life, Part 4
My name is Shinonome Nano.
I'm a robot, made by the
professor I live with.
The professor seems to be doing experiments,
so she stays home all day.
I spend my days helping her.
Professor, I warmed up some milk for you—
I don't have any special features,
but I can feel pain.
Nano, what's wrong?
Professor, my toe... My toe...
Y-Y-Your t-t-toe...
It should be all right now.
I don't have any special features,
but my toe comes off.
Professor, what is this key for?
Haven't I ever turned it?
You haven't. But occasionally, it spins.
If you turn it like this...
What's going on?
Excuse me. I do have special features.
See? Fun, isn't it?
Is that the only reason this key is here?
Of course.
That's the only reason for this key?
Of course!
Please remove it!
No!
It's cute.
I'm serious. Please remove it!
What? But it's cute...
I want to be more normal.
I want to sit in chairs normally
and roll over normally.
I can't go to school like this.
I wish I weren't an android.
Nano...
I-I'm just kidding!
You're being ridiculous, Professor.
Then take it...
What?
Take my Akutagawa Prize for literature!
Why?
Take my Akutagawa Prize!
This is my life.
Where am I?
Hello! I'm Nano-chan's big toe.
I'm quite small.
I wish I were a little bigger...
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 2.
Next Time    TITLE
Don't miss it.